<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reflections | Blog de Albert L.G.</title><link>https://albertlg.com/en/tag/reflections/</link><atom:link href="https://albertlg.com/en/tag/reflections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>reflections</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Created with ❤ by: Albert L.G. © 2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 13:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://albertlg.com/images/logo_hud73e1285fdf1afd60709ba56fd2a6df6_5032_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>reflections</title><link>https://albertlg.com/en/tag/reflections/</link></image><item><title>Tricefalia. Reflections of a Sponge</title><link>https://albertlg.com/en/tricefalia-reflections-sponge-1181188/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://albertlg.com/en/tricefalia-reflections-sponge-1181188/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
The song says it best: “&lt;a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/5STLuc2HvoD573BtHxxnUA">&lt;em>3 is a
magic number. Yes it is, is a magic number&lt;/em>&lt;/a>.” And I say
“says” in the present tense, because songs speak to us
&lt;strong>now&lt;/strong> (the very moment we listen to them). Good
songs never go out of style: they endure, they evolve with new
versions, they adapt.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
As of today...
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p style="text-decoration: line-through;">
at &lt;strong>home&lt;/strong>, my family is 3: my wife, my
daughter, and I
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>UPDATE&lt;/strong>: at &lt;strong>home&lt;/strong>, my family
is 3: my wife and my 2 daughters
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
our &lt;strong>work&lt;/strong> was built by 3 of us (though by now
we’re a bigger team... and we
&lt;strong>&lt;a title="molamos 3 huevos" href="https://albertlg.com/img/post/529e16ee4a91as6441.jpg">rock&lt;/a>
&lt;a title="molamos 3 huevos" href="https://albertlg.com/img/post/529e172271317s6249.jpg">3&lt;/a>
&lt;a title="molamos 3 huevos" href="https://albertlg.com/img/post/529e174f8fb38s8484.jpg">eggs&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>)
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
plus I like to share 1 of my 3
&lt;strong>passions&lt;/strong>—the most essential one, the one I
couldn’t live without—music, alongside 2 traveling companions:
a worldly Murcian and a Chilean with a Catalan heart, whose
every year of life reads like poetry (can you tell I’m writing
this post after a concert?). So, once again, we are 3.
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
Why “a sponge”? It’s simple: because in each of these 3 aspects
(the most important in my life: ‘family, work, and leisure’,
‘home, office, and recreation’, ‘loved ones, partners, and
friends’...), like a sponge, they either fill you to the brim or
squeeze you dry. And also because many times people have told me
I’m quite “absorbent” when it comes to those I care about—why
deny it?
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
And since I’ve always liked seeking
&lt;strong>balance&lt;/strong> (back to songs; this time it’s Piratas
reminding us that “&lt;a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/0rCWIsEuZlwgpIOWLfZEAA">&lt;em>el
equilibrio es imposible&lt;/em>&lt;/a>”), walking (or running or
jumping) the path (that’s where we learn, live, and enjoy), let’s
triangulate—or, well, reflect—and apply it wherever it fits:
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;strong>Organization! And flexibility.&lt;/strong> Don’t fall into
&lt;em>burrocracy&lt;/em>. Chart a route and (once in a while) take
a shortcut. To say “&lt;em>I love it when a plan comes together&lt;/em>,”
you need a plan first. Plan, organize yourself, and follow
workflows (but don’t chisel anything in stone).
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;strong>Think it over 2 or even 3 times. Let go and
improvise.&lt;/strong> This may sound contradictory, but I’m a
lover of relativity. It depends. Analyze each scenario (faster
or slower depending on the situation).
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;strong>Practice, practice, practice.&lt;/strong> Good results and
good habits demand it. “Test,” “rehearse,” and
“experiment”—it’s what great magicians do. And who doesn’t love
a bit of magic?
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;strong>Learn to teach and teach how to learn.&lt;/strong> The
secret? Listen. Sounds easy, huh? Give it a try. Listen.
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;strong>Speak up. Give others visibility, communication is
key.&lt;/strong> If you only listen, information won’t flow as it
should. You also have to voice your opinion to keep learning
or teaching. Besides, ensuring others are clear on what you
bring to the table is vital for good coordination.
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;strong>Pitch in, be supportive and understanding.&lt;/strong>
When you want something you’ve never achieved before, you’re
forced to do things you’ve never done, and that can cause fear,
vertigo, and uncertainty—for you as well as others. Help those
around you and let them help you. All for one and one for all!
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;strong>Offer to others and take what you need.&lt;/strong>
Delegate, but don’t forget to do your share (and set an
example). Though asking is easier than giving, the best way to
nurture any relationship is to start by giving and keep
striving for balance. It’s great for showcasing that
“tiqui-taca.” That’s how trust gearwork runs smoothly.
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;strong>Neither black nor white, but a scale of grays.&lt;/strong>
Avoid extremes, radicalism, and absolute truths. Remember that
sometimes a gray can be very light or very dark, and you can’t
stand between two waters forever—you have to take a stance.
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;strong>Motiva(te)—Motivate (yourself).&lt;/strong> It’s
fantastic to fuel your enthusiasm and keep a steady tempo.
Always encourage others to reach their goals, and place the
carrot just far enough to keep you moving at the pace you
desire/need.
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;strong>Have a lot of fun.&lt;/strong> What’s the point of life
otherwise? And smile.
&lt;a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/12HSHmcpsMdHPFWm2fks6b">&lt;em>Smile!&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
Finally, with all the &lt;strong>humility&lt;/strong> so appreciated at
&lt;a href="http://www.uvinum.es/">Uvinum&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/covertura">Covertura&lt;/a>, and
&lt;a href="http://albertlg.posterous.com/carnaval-3">home&lt;/a>—and
hoping this doesn’t sound like the usual “blah, blah, blah”—I
just want to say I shared these reflections to never forget
them, to always remember them. I’ve already forgotten them.
Let’s read them again. :)
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>