<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>philosofy | Blog de Albert L.G.</title><link>https://albertlg.com/en/tag/philosofy/</link><atom:link href="https://albertlg.com/en/tag/philosofy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>philosofy</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Created with ❤ by: Albert L.G. © 2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:13:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://albertlg.com/images/logo_hud73e1285fdf1afd60709ba56fd2a6df6_5032_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>philosofy</title><link>https://albertlg.com/en/tag/philosofy/</link></image><item><title>Between Hoops and Flashes: A Journey into the Heart of Basketball in Badalona</title><link>https://albertlg.com/en/hoops-flashes-journey-heart-of-basketball-in-badalona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:13:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://albertlg.com/en/hoops-flashes-journey-heart-of-basketball-in-badalona/</guid><description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html>
&lt;html lang="en">
&lt;head>
&lt;meta charset="UTF-8">
&lt;title>Between Hoops and Flashes: A Journey into the Heart of Basketball in Badalona&lt;/title>
&lt;meta name="description" content="Discover how the passion for basketball spans generations in Badalona, the ‘bressol’ of Catalan hoops. I share my experience as a player, coach, and father of two rising players in the Penya and UB Llefià.">
&lt;/head>
&lt;body>
&lt;h1>Between Hoops and Flashes: A Journey into the Heart of Basketball in Badalona&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>
A few days ago, while taking my daughter &lt;strong>Laia (almost 12)&lt;/strong> to her training sessions
with the &lt;em>Penya&lt;/em> (Club Joventut Badalona) and &lt;strong>Alba (16, just turned)&lt;/strong> to &lt;em>UB Llefià&lt;/em>,
I realized just how deeply this sport brings us together as a family.
But in truth, it also unites an entire city that &lt;strong>breathes basketball&lt;/strong>: &lt;strong>Badalona&lt;/strong>,
seen as the true “bressol del basquetbol” (cradle of basketball) in Catalonia.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
In my case, I started out as a player and then became a
&lt;strong>coach under the Federació Catalana de Basquetbol&lt;/strong>. I’ve experienced the intensity
of games, the thrill of victories, and the sting of defeats firsthand; but above all, I’ve soaked up
(like the &lt;em>sponge&lt;/em> I am) everything that happens on and off the court.
And now I get to see that same passion mirrored in my daughters, each following her own path in the sport.
It fills me with immense pride.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Badalona: a city shaped by basketball&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
When people talk about &lt;strong>Badalona&lt;/strong> and basketball, it seems impossible to separate the two.
As early as the beginning of the 20th century, the seeds of this sport were planted here,
and it has since captivated a huge number of fans. The most iconic club,
&lt;strong>Penya&lt;/strong>, was founded in 1930 and over the decades has not only claimed national
and international titles, but also become part of the identity of multiple generations.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Still, basketball’s strength in Badalona isn’t limited to just one club.
There are schools, youth academies, and &lt;em>local teams&lt;/em> fostering and expanding this basketball culture.
That’s why it’s no surprise to see so many people walking around with a ball under their arm,
or to find countless public courts bringing life to the streets and parks.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Naismith’s legacy: the 13 rules that started it all&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
Talking about the cradle of basketball leads me to think of its inventor, &lt;strong>Dr. James Naismith&lt;/strong>.
In December of 1891, seeking an indoor activity to keep his students fit during winter,
he created this sport at the YMCA in Springfield. That’s where he first hung two peach baskets
and outlined the game’s initial structure.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
His &lt;strong>13 original rules&lt;/strong> —published in 1892— were simple yet powerful.
From forbidding players to run with the ball to the rule against punching it,
they established a sport that prized skill and teamwork over brute force.
Over time, elements like dribbling, the shot clock, and the three-point line emerged,
but Naismith’s spirit remains at its core: &lt;em>the essence of a team game&lt;/em>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Why I call it “magic”&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
Basketball isn’t just about scoring: it’s about &lt;strong>wordless communication&lt;/strong> between teammates,
making split-second decisions, and encouraging collective effort instead of individual glory.
That, to me, is the big trick. And like an aspiring magician,
I strive to pass it on to my daughters and every team I've coached.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Between the board and the court: my view as a coach and parent&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
When I first became a coach, I believed my role was &lt;em>solely&lt;/em> to teach:
offensive systems, zone defenses, technical fundamentals...
It didn’t take me long to discover I was actually the first student.
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Learning to lead without imposing:&lt;/strong> Basketball calls for initiative and creativity. You can’t stifle each player’s talent.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Listening to grow:&lt;/strong> Some of my best &lt;em>“plays”&lt;/em> have come from the advice of players half my age.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Emotional management:&lt;/strong> Victory or defeat, no one is immune to what happens on the court. Knowing how to channel it is crucial for success.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
Being &lt;strong>Alba&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Laia's&lt;/strong> father adds yet another layer to the story.
I take them to their practices and games, trying not to overstep into their routines,
but always being their biggest fan. I see how sports shape their character, their resilience,
their friendships... and I feel lucky to witness it firsthand.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>What does this sport teach us beyond the hardwood?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
In my last article, I talked about being a &lt;strong>“sponge”&lt;/strong> and “squeezing ourselves” daily
to learn something new in our family life, at work, and during our free time.
Though it may sound poetic, I’m still convinced that life is &lt;em>richer&lt;/em>
when we know how to absorb —and also share— the experiences and advice of those around us.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Basketball is a prime example: it &lt;strong>requires listening&lt;/strong> (to the coach and the rest of the team),
&lt;strong>demands communication&lt;/strong> (passes, plays, strategy), and &lt;strong>forces you to adapt&lt;/strong>
to a thousand different situations. Whoever masters these aspects on the court will, without realizing it,
carry them into everyday life.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Final thoughts: glimpses of the future&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
As I write these words, I’m wondering what the future holds for my daughters, for Penya, for UB Llefià,
and for basketball in general. Maybe tomorrow’s hoops will be full of sensors,
and games will be played in high-tech arenas; but I’m certain that, just like today,
the essence of &lt;strong>our passion for the game&lt;/strong> will remain untouched.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
As for me, I’ll keep on supporting my daughters every step of the way, both on and off the court,
preserving the spirit of that younger self who once played the game and then dared to coach,
in this one-of-a-kind city called &lt;strong>Badalona&lt;/strong>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>And how about you?&lt;/strong> What burst of passion fuels your life?
Maybe it isn’t basketball, but there’s probably a sport or hobby that drives you to become better.
I encourage you to squeeze yourself like the best sponge: &lt;em>absorb, share, and keep moving forward&lt;/em>.
See you in the next play!
&lt;/p>
&lt;/body>
&lt;/html></description></item></channel></rss>